From Monday to Friday, many of us have an early start and a long day.
周一到周五，我们很多人都早起晚归。
By the time we've gone to bed and managed to fall asleep, we've been woken up by the alarm to do it all again.
等到好不容易上床入睡，闹钟又会把我们叫醒，开启新的一天。
Come the weekend, and we're totally exhausted.
到了周末，我们早已筋疲力尽。
We sleep in way past our usual wake-up time just to stay in sync enough to start again on Monday.
为了能在周一重新振作，我们会睡到大中午，远远超过平时的起床时间。
Welcome to social jet lag.
这就是“社交时差”。
That's the term for the disparity between our working-week sleeping pattern, when our sleep times relate to our responsibilities, and the weekend, when we can wake when we choose.
这个术语指的是工作日和周末睡眠模式的差异：工作日的睡眠时间要配合工作和责任，而周末我们可以随心所欲地起床。
And depending on what type of person you are, the difference can be significant.
根据个人类型不同，这种差异可能会非常明显。
For night owls - those whose natural rhythm is to wake and go to bed later - there can be significant health-related issues, according to a recent study published by Taylor and Francis Group online.
泰勒&弗朗西斯集团近期在网上发布的一项研究表明，对于夜猫子——那些天生习惯晚睡晚起的人来说，这可能会引发严重的健康问题。
The study concludes the further the divergence between working-week and weekend sleep times, the greater the health issues – including a higher risk of heart disease and other metabolic problems.
研究得出结论：工作日和周末的睡眠时间差异越大，健康问题就越严重，包括患心脏病和其他代谢疾病的风险更高。
And because so many jobs and tasks start early, night owls are effectively forced into harmonising with the early birds.
而且由于很多工作和任务都需要早起，夜猫子们实际上被迫要和早起的人保持一致的作息。
So what can night owls do: force themselves to integrate by sacrificing their lie in?
那么夜猫子们该怎么办呢？
'It's the worst thing you can do' says Professor Till Roenneberg, professor of chronobiology at the Institute of Medical Psychology at Ludwig-Maximilian University in Munich.
难道要牺牲赖床时间，强迫自己融入早起的作息吗？
This is because people's sleep pattern is half determined by genetics.
慕尼黑路德维希-马克西米利安大学医学心理学研究所的时间生物学教授蒂尔·伦内伯格说：“这是最糟糕的做法。”
The other half correlates with their age and environment.
因为人的睡眠模式一半由基因决定，另一半与年龄和环境相关。
Getting less sleep is unlikely to realign your genetic tendencies.
减少睡眠并不能改变你的基因倾向。
Our bodies evolved to coordinate with the rise and fall of the Sun.
我们的身体进化得与太阳的升落保持同步。
We should feel sleepy as the light dissipates.
当光线逐渐消失时，我们就会感到困倦。
But modern life, with its artificial light and modern devices, such as computers and smartphones, means we have deviated.
但现代生活中的人造光源和电脑、智能手机等电子设备，让我们偏离了这种自然节律。
Now we are exposed to more light for longer periods of time, keeping our bodies awake longer.
现在我们暴露在光线中的时间更长，这让身体保持清醒的时间也随之延长。
For night owls, who already tend to sleep later, this delays things even further.
对于本就倾向于晚睡的夜猫子来说，这会让他们的入睡时间更晚。
One solution, beyond changing society's early-start tendencies, is to reorient our body clock by manipulating our exposure to light.
除了改变社会普遍早起的趋势之外，还有一个解决方案：通过控制光照来调整生物钟。
By taking more sunlight in the morning and minimising the amount of artificial light we are exposed to in the evening – particularly on electronic devices - we can rebalance our bodies to feel sleepy earlier.
早上多晒太阳，晚上尽量减少人造光源的接触——尤其是电子设备发出的光线——这样可以重新平衡身体状态，让我们更早感到困倦。
It's far from easy, but better that than losing your whole weekend to sleep.
这绝非易事，但总比整个周末都用来补觉要好。